<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on CamMakoJ</title>
    <link>/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on CamMakoJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 13:24:38 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Headed Fishing</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/fishing-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 13:24:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/fishing-trip/</guid>
      <description>I am headed up North to fish near Jasper this weekend. I am pretty excited I&amp;rsquo;ve never been up that way before and its with some good buddies. I have been prepping so far this week by tying up some flies, which I am still learning but there are some simpler streamer patterns that I&amp;rsquo;m not too bad at.
This is just a little taste of what I was working on&amp;hellip; hopefully I will be able to post that some of these flies were super effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Failure</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/books-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 09:26:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/books-failure/</guid>
      <description>I have been trying to read more lately, and by read its been mostly audiobooks. I recently discovered that I can use my local libraries online system to get both e-books and audiobooks on my phone for free which is awesome!
Check out Libby it is an awesome front end for using your local library resources, and at least where I live its totally free. Definitely worth checking out if you like reading or listening to books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:07:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I have long wanted to blog more consistently but always got bogged down in what service to use, and how to use it&amp;hellip; or whether I should wait until I could build one myself. Fortunately I came to my senses and no longer think building it from scratch myself makes sense, so I went with a happy medium and am using Hugo and firebase for my needs. Hopefully this helps me learn a bit of website management as well as some more &amp;lsquo;coding&amp;rsquo; skills in my quest for a better understanding of the web.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>