<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geomatics on CamMakoJ</title>
    <link>/categories/geomatics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geomatics on CamMakoJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 10:44:45 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/geomatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Expressions in a QGIS Atlas</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/june/qgis-atlas-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 10:44:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/june/qgis-atlas-expressions/</guid>
      <description>It has taken me a long time to get comfortable with the print composer in QGIS. I think for me the biggest issue is once you hit that composer you need to combine all the data you have worked with and make it look appealing while conveying the message you are trying to tell with the map. It&amp;rsquo;s art, it&amp;rsquo;s science, it&amp;rsquo;s cartography! It also can be a very fun part of telling the data&amp;rsquo;s story and I love maps for that as they can show a lot in a simple way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AER Shapefile Submissions</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/may/aer-shapefile-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 11:49:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/may/aer-shapefile-submissions/</guid>
      <description>The AER One Stop is a great regulator solution to some of the uncertainty in project delivery, such as to who to send what to. However it has created some confusion on its own that I have dealt with when formatting shapefiles for upload to the site. I have really only used this feature as part of Water Activities and they have since released guidelines on how to ensure your shapefile complies with their filters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer Fun</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/may/geoserver-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:42:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/may/geoserver-fun/</guid>
      <description>I got this big idea in my head that I wanted to make it easier for co-workers to access the treasure trove of GIS data I have been collecting. Mostly just standard public datasets, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to pull them into your GIS Environment and view them along with the other layers your looking at. Originally I had setup a bunch of geopackages on dropbox to organize and share the datasets, however this required each user to download a local copy of the data and wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly efficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a DEM from Contours</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/contours-dem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 15:02:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/contours-dem/</guid>
      <description>Contours Contours are a great way to visualize topography on a flat map without covering background imagery. It is often great for figures where you want a visible basemap.
Digital Elevation Model That being said it is nice to have a digital elevation model (DEM) for easier interpretation of what the ground is looking like. I find this easier to see where there are steep slopes and depressions that may be wetlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QGIS Processor Modelling</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/qgis-processor-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 17:03:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/qgis-processor-modelling/</guid>
      <description>Constraints Mapping I had a project where I needed to look at constraints mapping for a series of project areas. Essentially I needed to look at a project and see what parts and how many layers it intersected with. The first thing I wanted to look at was how to go about automating as much as I could and since my python skills are still very green I looked into using the new to me QGIS process modeler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeafletJS Maps</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/leafletmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 11:03:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/leafletmaps/</guid>
      <description>LeafletJS Leaflet JS is a javascript library for the creation of web maps. I wanted to use it to create a simple web-map for viewing the Alberta Merged Wetland Inventory (AMWI) streamed via a web map service (WMS). Eventually I would like to be able to upload a shapefile to zoom to an area and determine if an area does intersect any mapped wetlands. To access the WMS for the AMWI I used the links available in Alberta&amp;rsquo;s open data portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:07:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I have long wanted to blog more consistently but always got bogged down in what service to use, and how to use it&amp;hellip; or whether I should wait until I could build one myself. Fortunately I came to my senses and no longer think building it from scratch myself makes sense, so I went with a happy medium and am using Hugo and firebase for my needs. Hopefully this helps me learn a bit of website management as well as some more &amp;lsquo;coding&amp;rsquo; skills in my quest for a better understanding of the web.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>