<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geomatics on CamMakoJ</title>
    <link>/categories/geomatics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geomatics on CamMakoJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 15:02:33 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/geomatics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a DEM from Contours</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/contours-dem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 15:02:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/contours-dem/</guid>
      <description>Contours Contours are a great way to visualize topography on a flat map without covering background imagery. It is often great for figures where you want a visible basemap.
Digital Elevation Model That being said it is nice to have a digital elevation model (DEM) for easier interpretation of what the ground is looking like. I find this easier to see where there are steep slopes and depressions that may be wetlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QGIS Processor Modelling</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/qgis-processor-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 17:03:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/qgis-processor-modelling/</guid>
      <description>Constraints Mapping I had a project where I needed to look at constraints mapping for a series of project areas. Essentially I needed to look at a project and see what parts and how many layers it intersected with. The first thing I wanted to look at was how to go about automating as much as I could and since my python skills are still very green I looked into using the new to me QGIS process modeler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeafletJS Maps</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/leafletmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 11:03:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/leafletmaps/</guid>
      <description>LeafletJS Leaflet JS is a javascript library for the creation of web maps. I wanted to use it to create a simple web-map for viewing the Alberta Merged Wetland Inventory (AMWI) streamed via a web map service (WMS). Eventually I would like to be able to upload a shapefile to zoom to an area and determine if an area does intersect any mapped wetlands. To access the WMS for the AMWI I used the links available in Alberta&amp;rsquo;s open data portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:07:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I have long wanted to blog more consistently but always got bogged down in what service to use, and how to use it&amp;hellip; or whether I should wait until I could build one myself. Fortunately I came to my senses and no longer think building it from scratch myself makes sense, so I went with a happy medium and am using Hugo and firebase for my needs. Hopefully this helps me learn a bit of website management as well as some more &amp;lsquo;coding&amp;rsquo; skills in my quest for a better understanding of the web.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>