<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on CamMakoJ</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on CamMakoJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 17:03:46 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>QGIS Processor Modelling</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/qgis-processor-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 17:03:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/qgis-processor-modelling/</guid>
      <description>Constraints Mapping I had a project where I needed to look at constraints mapping for a series of project areas. Essentially I needed to look at a project and see what parts and how many layers it intersected with. The first thing I wanted to look at was how to go about automating as much as I could and since my python skills are still very green I looked into using the new to me QGIS process modeler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Failure</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/books-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 09:26:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/books-failure/</guid>
      <description>I have been trying to read more lately, and by read its been mostly audiobooks. I recently discovered that I can use my local libraries online system to get both e-books and audiobooks on my phone for free which is awesome!
Check out Libby it is an awesome front end for using your local library resources, and at least where I live its totally free. Definitely worth checking out if you like reading or listening to books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeafletJS Maps</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/leafletmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 11:03:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/leafletmaps/</guid>
      <description>LeafletJS Leaflet JS is a javascript library for the creation of web maps. I wanted to use it to create a simple web-map for viewing the Alberta Merged Wetland Inventory (AMWI) streamed via a web map service (WMS). Eventually I would like to be able to upload a shapefile to zoom to an area and determine if an area does intersect any mapped wetlands. To access the WMS for the AMWI I used the links available in Alberta&amp;rsquo;s open data portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACIMS App</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/acims-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:07:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/acims-app/</guid>
      <description>I started working on a write up of the ACIMS app that I made as a project. The intent of the writeup is both so that I can document what I did properly, but also so that I can hopefully share with others the process I went through. Though this is mostly to help me improve my understanding of what I have worked on, as having not re-visited it in awhile its very easy to forget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:07:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I have long wanted to blog more consistently but always got bogged down in what service to use, and how to use it&amp;hellip; or whether I should wait until I could build one myself. Fortunately I came to my senses and no longer think building it from scratch myself makes sense, so I went with a happy medium and am using Hugo and firebase for my needs. Hopefully this helps me learn a bit of website management as well as some more &amp;lsquo;coding&amp;rsquo; skills in my quest for a better understanding of the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favourite Photos</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/my-favourite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 19:56:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/my-favourite/</guid>
      <description>2nd
3rd
5th
7th
`</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Shots</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/old-shots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 19:56:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/old-shots/</guid>
      <description>1st
10th
11th
12th
13th
16th
19th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos of Ralph and Other Dogs</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/ralph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 19:56:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/ralph/</guid>
      <description>1st
4th
6th
Ralph pose
`</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>