<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on CamMakoJ</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on CamMakoJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 11:15:08 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender Topography Maps of Alberta</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/february/blender-topo-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 11:15:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/february/blender-topo-maps/</guid>
      <description>Acquiring Our Data I have seen some really cool applications of DEM models in blender. I have done a bit of messing around in blender previously, however it&amp;rsquo;s been awhile and I never really got very good at it. So we shall see how this goes, but i&amp;rsquo;m taking a crack at importing the province of Alberta&amp;rsquo;s 25m DEM from Altalis. It is a public dataset so if you want to snag it head here Altalis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a DEM and getting Simplified Contours</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/september/simplifying-contours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 11:15:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/september/simplifying-contours/</guid>
      <description>When creating contours from high resolution DEM data you can often have a lot of distracting artifacts for small areas with slight deviations in topography. Depending on the final resolution of your end product and the intent of the maps you are creating it may be beneficial to reduce the resolution of the DEM so that your contours are simplified. This is a lossy process and the contours will lose detail but the cost is offset by readability, which can often be worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a DEM to get Slope Directions</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/august/slope-direction-from-dem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 11:15:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/august/slope-direction-from-dem/</guid>
      <description>To properly assess wetlands it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand what is happening to surface water at and near the wetland itself. If you have a digital elevation model from LIDAR or something similar then you can look at visually to determine the catchment areas and slope direction, however in some cases I find the overall surface to be too flat to effectively do this visually. I also find that using software to do the math is a lot easier&amp;hellip; and more reproducible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Shapefiles into a GPX</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/july/shapefiles-to-gpx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 15:53:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/july/shapefiles-to-gpx/</guid>
      <description>Quite often for environmental field work I need to convert shapefiles or other GIS formats into GPX files. Now this would seem like it should be a simple task for the mighty QGIS. However in many cases its not as simple as hitting export and choosing the gpx file type. What I have found is super helpful is considering what I typically see in GPX files. Routes, Tracks, and Waypoints. This is a little different then the points, lines, and polygons of the shapefile world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avenza Georeferenced Maps in QGIS</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/july/qgis-avenza-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 16:05:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/july/qgis-avenza-maps/</guid>
      <description>I have tried using Avenza PDF in the past on my phone but was never able to get an easily exportable map to work with it from QGIS. That was until I actually tried to google around a bit and figure out how to make it work. I am using QGIS 3.2 so was unable to use some of the plugins that I had found as they were for earlier versions of QGIS and haven&amp;rsquo;t been updated at this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Expressions in a QGIS Atlas</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/june/qgis-atlas-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 10:44:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/june/qgis-atlas-expressions/</guid>
      <description>It has taken me a long time to get comfortable with the print composer in QGIS. I think for me the biggest issue is once you hit that composer you need to combine all the data you have worked with and make it look appealing while conveying the message you are trying to tell with the map. It&amp;rsquo;s art, it&amp;rsquo;s science, it&amp;rsquo;s cartography! It also can be a very fun part of telling the data&amp;rsquo;s story and I love maps for that as they can show a lot in a simple way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AER Shapefile Submissions</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/may/aer-shapefile-submissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 11:49:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/may/aer-shapefile-submissions/</guid>
      <description>The AER One Stop is a great regulator solution to some of the uncertainty in project delivery, such as to who to send what to. However it has created some confusion on its own that I have dealt with when formatting shapefiles for upload to the site. I have really only used this feature as part of Water Activities and they have since released guidelines on how to ensure your shapefile complies with their filters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ralphy Boy</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/may/ralph-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 12:25:54 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/may/ralph-boy/</guid>
      <description>Our little dude Ralph is pretty awesome. We have been working pretty hard to get him trained up&amp;hellip; so hopefully one day he can come fishing with me. So far he has been with me for some short fishing sessions of an hour or so, but never longer&amp;hellip; he starts to get bored, and he isn&amp;rsquo;t at the place I can totally trust him off leash just yet. He also hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a huge fan of the water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping in Alberta</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/may/camping-fallentimber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 14:22:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/may/camping-fallentimber/</guid>
      <description>I love getting out of town and camping. It&amp;rsquo;s just so nice to spend all day outside and finish the night around a campfire and fall asleep in a tent to the quiet sounds of a stream. It was super nice to get out and fish with my dad as well. We were lucky enough to get into a few brown trout, which are my favourite. I was hoping with the warm weather we would be able to have some success on the dry, but they were only sub-surface feeding while we were there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sous Vide - Gochujang Fried Chicken</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/may/cooking-gochujang-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 16:38:34 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/may/cooking-gochujang-chicken/</guid>
      <description>I fell in love with gochujang when I went for Korean BBQ the first time with a friend. It&amp;rsquo;s subtle and sweet spice is delicious in so many unique ways. I found a recipe for my Anova sous-vide on their site and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to try it.
Overall it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much work and it definitely was good practice with frying in the pan. That same friend who introduced me to gochujang also showed me some better frying technique when he made me some mad good spring rolls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoServer Fun</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/may/geoserver-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 13:42:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/may/geoserver-fun/</guid>
      <description>I got this big idea in my head that I wanted to make it easier for co-workers to access the treasure trove of GIS data I have been collecting. Mostly just standard public datasets, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to pull them into your GIS Environment and view them along with the other layers your looking at. Originally I had setup a bunch of geopackages on dropbox to organize and share the datasets, however this required each user to download a local copy of the data and wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly efficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fishing the Athabasca River</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/fishing-athabasca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 23:20:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/fishing-athabasca/</guid>
      <description>Athabasca falls
Athabasca falls2
Athabasca river
Colombia icefields
Echo base 7wt
I went on a trip to the Athabasca river with some friends. It was a gorgeous place to visit and we stayed in Jasper at a great AirBnB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Headed Fishing</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/fishing-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 13:24:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/fishing-trip/</guid>
      <description>I am headed up North to fish near Jasper this weekend. I am pretty excited I&amp;rsquo;ve never been up that way before and its with some good buddies. I have been prepping so far this week by tying up some flies, which I am still learning but there are some simpler streamer patterns that I&amp;rsquo;m not too bad at.
This is just a little taste of what I was working on&amp;hellip; hopefully I will be able to post that some of these flies were super effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a DEM from Contours</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/contours-dem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 15:02:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/contours-dem/</guid>
      <description>Contours Contours are a great way to visualize topography on a flat map without covering background imagery. It is often great for figures where you want a visible basemap.
Digital Elevation Model That being said it is nice to have a digital elevation model (DEM) for easier interpretation of what the ground is looking like. I find this easier to see where there are steep slopes and depressions that may be wetlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QGIS Processor Modelling</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/qgis-processor-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 17:03:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/qgis-processor-modelling/</guid>
      <description>Constraints Mapping I had a project where I needed to look at constraints mapping for a series of project areas. Essentially I needed to look at a project and see what parts and how many layers it intersected with. The first thing I wanted to look at was how to go about automating as much as I could and since my python skills are still very green I looked into using the new to me QGIS process modeler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Failure</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/books-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 09:26:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/books-failure/</guid>
      <description>I have been trying to read more lately, and by read its been mostly audiobooks. I recently discovered that I can use my local libraries online system to get both e-books and audiobooks on my phone for free which is awesome!
Check out Libby it is an awesome front end for using your local library resources, and at least where I live its totally free. Definitely worth checking out if you like reading or listening to books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LeafletJS Maps</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/leafletmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 11:03:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/leafletmaps/</guid>
      <description>LeafletJS Leaflet JS is a javascript library for the creation of web maps. I wanted to use it to create a simple web-map for viewing the Alberta Merged Wetland Inventory (AMWI) streamed via a web map service (WMS). Eventually I would like to be able to upload a shapefile to zoom to an area and determine if an area does intersect any mapped wetlands. To access the WMS for the AMWI I used the links available in Alberta&amp;rsquo;s open data portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACIMS App</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/acims-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:07:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/acims-app/</guid>
      <description>I started working on a write up of the ACIMS app that I made as a project. The intent of the writeup is both so that I can document what I did properly, but also so that I can hopefully share with others the process I went through. Though this is mostly to help me improve my understanding of what I have worked on, as having not re-visited it in awhile its very easy to forget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 23:07:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/first-post/</guid>
      <description>I have long wanted to blog more consistently but always got bogged down in what service to use, and how to use it&amp;hellip; or whether I should wait until I could build one myself. Fortunately I came to my senses and no longer think building it from scratch myself makes sense, so I went with a happy medium and am using Hugo and firebase for my needs. Hopefully this helps me learn a bit of website management as well as some more &amp;lsquo;coding&amp;rsquo; skills in my quest for a better understanding of the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favourite Photos</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/my-favourite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 19:56:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/my-favourite/</guid>
      <description>2nd
3rd
5th
7th
`</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Shots</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/old-shots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 19:56:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/old-shots/</guid>
      <description>1st
10th
11th
12th
13th
16th
19th
21st
22nd
23rd
24th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos of Ralph and Other Dogs</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/ralph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 19:56:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/ralph/</guid>
      <description>1st
4th
6th
Ralph pose
`</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>