<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DEM on CamMakoJ</title>
    <link>/tags/dem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DEM on CamMakoJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 11:15:08 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/dem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender Topography Maps of Alberta</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/february/blender-topo-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 11:15:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/february/blender-topo-maps/</guid>
      <description>Acquiring Our Data I have seen some really cool applications of DEM models in blender. I have done a bit of messing around in blender previously, however it&amp;rsquo;s been awhile and I never really got very good at it. So we shall see how this goes, but i&amp;rsquo;m taking a crack at importing the province of Alberta&amp;rsquo;s 25m DEM from Altalis. It is a public dataset so if you want to snag it head here Altalis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a DEM and getting Simplified Contours</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/september/simplifying-contours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 11:15:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/september/simplifying-contours/</guid>
      <description>When creating contours from high resolution DEM data you can often have a lot of distracting artifacts for small areas with slight deviations in topography. Depending on the final resolution of your end product and the intent of the maps you are creating it may be beneficial to reduce the resolution of the DEM so that your contours are simplified. This is a lossy process and the contours will lose detail but the cost is offset by readability, which can often be worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a DEM to get Slope Directions</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/august/slope-direction-from-dem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 11:15:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/august/slope-direction-from-dem/</guid>
      <description>To properly assess wetlands it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand what is happening to surface water at and near the wetland itself. If you have a digital elevation model from LIDAR or something similar then you can look at visually to determine the catchment areas and slope direction, however in some cases I find the overall surface to be too flat to effectively do this visually. I also find that using software to do the math is a lot easier&amp;hellip; and more reproducible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a DEM from Contours</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/april/contours-dem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 15:02:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/april/contours-dem/</guid>
      <description>Contours Contours are a great way to visualize topography on a flat map without covering background imagery. It is often great for figures where you want a visible basemap.
Digital Elevation Model That being said it is nice to have a digital elevation model (DEM) for easier interpretation of what the ground is looking like. I find this easier to see where there are steep slopes and depressions that may be wetlands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>